Aleksandar Medarevic

Sajkaska 23, Palilula, 39/6, 11000 Belgrade, Serbia | aco.batut@gmail.com | BioLink | RGB



Profile

I am a medical doctor and indepentent public health researcher with over seven year of experience in the public health field. I focus on clinical coding, populationbased health management, health care emergencies, drug use, epidemiology and health economy.

Skills

Statistics • • • • •

R, SPSS, STATA, EndNote, RevMan, QGis, EpiInfo, Python

Computer skills

● ● ● ●

Windows, Office, Adobe, Corel

Research skills

● ● ● ●

All steps in research process

Coding and programmingHTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, R

Web Design

● ●

WordPress, Frontend design

Projects

- Population Health Information Research Infrastructure (PHIRI) project

2021 - present

- Zdravo, rastimo Nestlé for Healthier Kids- Nestle Adriatic

2018 - present

- EHAction - Joint Action supporting the Ehealth Network

2019 - 2021

Meberships

Health Systems Global, member, 2022-

Serbian Medical Chamber, (Licence 113959)

The Global Burden of Diseases, collaborator

The Cochrane Library, collaborator

International Society of Global Health, , member

Professional Experience

Public health officer, *Institute of Public Health of Serbia* 2012 – present

Intership, *Medical Military Academy* 05/2011 – 12/2011

Education

Doctor of Philosophy, *University of Belgrade*

2014 - 2022

Public Health, Public Health Policy, Healthcare

Residency in Social Medicine,

Univesity of Belgrade, Scool of Medicine

2017 - 2020

Medical doctor, University of Belgrade, School of Medicine

2004 - 2011 9.07/10.00

Courses

Design and Interpretation of Clinical Trials(4QD9SLX7EFB), John Hopikins University and Coursera

Introduction to Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis (FCYCE5FNL9A), John Hopkins University and Coursera

Health Impact Assessment, step by step,

NCCHPP (Canada)

Languages

English

C1 Level

South Slavic languages

Fluent

German

Basic knowledge

References

Vesna Bjegovic Mikanovic, Vicedean, Prof.dr,

University of Belgrade

bjegov@med.bg.ac.rs

Djordje Alempijevic, *Professor*, University of Belgrade dalempijevic@hotmail.com

Dejana Vukovic, *Prof.dr*, University of Belgrade dejana.vukovic@med.bg.ac.rs

Aleksandar Medarević,

On date: 30.10.2022

M21 journals:

1. <u>Medarević A</u>, Vuković D. Efficiency and Productivity of Public Hospitals in Serbia Using DEA-Malmquist Model and Tobit Regression Model, 2015–2019. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 2021 Nov;18(23):12475. doi: 10.3390/ijerph182312475.

M22 journals:

2. Bogdanovic M, Hadzibegovic A, Medarevic A, Babic M, Jecmenica D, Alempijevic D. Discordance between clinical and post-mortem diagnoses at a tertiary hospital. Med Sci Law. 2020;60(1):11-15. doi:10.1177/0025802419878314

M23 journals:

- 3. <u>Medarevic A.</u> Performance evaluation of general public hospitals in territories of the Former Yugoslavia: An ecological study using the Pabon Lasso model. Int J Health Plan M. 2022 Mar 24. doi: 10.1002/hpm.3453
- Medarevic AP. Describing Serbian Hospital Activity Using Australian Refined Diagnosis Related Groups: A Case Study in Vojvodina Province. Zdr Varst. 2020;59(1):18-26. doi:10.2478/sjph-2020-0003
- 5. Jovanovic M, Medarevic A, Knezevic M, Krstic V. Mechanical eye injuries in children aged 0-15 years treated at the clinic of eye diseases in Belgrade: frequency, causes and preventive measures. Srp Arh Celok Lek. 2013;141(9-10):586-91. doi:10.2298/sarh1310586j

M52 journals:

6. <u>Medarević AP</u>, Vuković D. Productivity and efficiency in the health care system with special focus on hospital performance. Medicinski podmladak. 2022;73(3):27-32.

M53 journals:

- 7. Jovanovic M, Medarevic A. Conditions for good forensic expertise. Svet rada. 2018; 15(2): 116-24.
- 8. Jovanovic M, <u>Medarevic A</u>. Treatment of forensic expertise in court lawyers experts. Svet rada. 2017; 14(2): 118-25.
- 9. Jovanovic M, <u>Medarevic A</u>, Ivanovic I. Mortality of firearms in Serbia: Proposal of preventive measures and judicial discussion. Svet rada. 2015; 12(2): 2019-32.

Other peer-reviewed journals:

- 10. <u>Medarević A</u>. Trends in consumption and use of antidepressants and benzodiazepines in the Republic of Serbia in the period 2006-2019. Glasnik javnog zdravlja. 2022;96(2):126-35.
- 11. Jovanovic M, <u>Medarevic A</u>. Forensci medical expertise in court. Acta Ophthalmologica. 2016; 42(2): 20-24.

International conferences:

- 12. Kilibarda B, Simonovic P, <u>Medarevic A</u>, Jovanovic V, Vasic M, Misic I, Zajeganovic-Jakovljevic J. Substance use prevention among migrant children in Serbia-challenges and opportunities: Biljana Kilibarda. European Journal of Public Health. 2022;32(Supplement_3):ckac131-516.
- 13. <u>Medarević A</u>, Saso M, Krstić M. The health information portal for access and dissemination of population health-related information in europe. 54st days of preventive medicine, Nis 2022. Book of Abstract:189.

- 14. Čolović Čalovski I, Kačarević H, Mijatović S, <u>Medarević A</u>, Velimirović S, Džamić A. Intestinal parasitic infections in migrants passing through Serbia. 13th European Multicolloquium of Parasitology, Belgrade 2021. Book of Abstract:87.
- 15. Jakovljevic M, Matejic B, <u>Medarevic A</u>, et al. Mental health service use among university students with adverse childhood experiences. European Journal of Public Health. 2019;29 (Supplement_4):ckz186. 568.
- 16. Živković Šulović M, Brcanski J, <u>Medarević A</u>, Dobraš M. Satisfaction with child dentist services in Serbia 2017. 52nd days of preventive medicine, Nis 2018. Book of Abstract:198.
- 17. Živković Šulović M, Ivanovic I, <u>Medarević A</u>. Registered health status of migrants before and after the closure of the Balkan route. 51st days of preventive medicine, Nis 2017. Book of Abstract:62.
- 18. <u>Medarevic A</u>. Health status amongst migrants in Serbia during European migrant crisis: Aleksandar Medarevic. European Journal of Public Health. 2016;26 (suppl_1)
- 19. <u>Medarević A</u>, Jaćović Knežević N, Ilić D. Analyses of "A list" medicines needs for health organisations in Republic of Serbia in 2016. Treći kongres socijalne medicine "Zdravlje 2020. u Srbiji", Zlatibor. Zbornik radova i rezimea: 50-51.